All right well good afternoon everybody good to see you welcome
下午好，很高兴见到你们，欢迎
Welcome to all those students watching on video as well
也欢迎所有观看视频的学生
Before we start we were talking about joinable and detached threads
开始之前，我们讨论一下可结合（joinable）的线程和分离（detached）的线程（P694）
And you asked the question about why you would ever want to have threads running in non detached mode
上次课，你问了什么情况下需要使用线程的可结合的模式
You know why you'd ever run in want to have him running joinable
为什么要使用可结合的模式
And I didn't give you a very good answer so I want to try to to answer that for you better
上次课我没能很好的解释，这次课我希望能解释清楚一点
Turns out there's an important class of sort of parallel programming
实际上，有一类很重要的并发编程
There's an important parallel programming model called fork and join
这种并发编程模型叫做「fork」和「join」 （分叉和汇合）
Where program consists of a series of phases
在这种模型中，程序由一系列阶段组成
In each phase you have a worker or a master sorry
在每个阶段，都有多个工作线程和一个管理线程
And it creates a bunch of worker threads
程序会创建多个工作线程
And then each of those worker threads solve some part of the problem for that phase
然后，每个工作线程解决该阶段的某些问题
Like some maybe you take your data structure and you break it up into chunks
在程序中，你可能使用某种可以切分成多个部分的数据结构
And then each thread updates the its own chunk of that data structure
然后每个线程更新其该数据结构中的某个块
But for whatever reason the master then has to wait for the worker threads to finish before it can go on to the next phase
但出于某种原因，管理线程必须等待所有的工作线程完成才能进入下一阶段
So it does join, so this is called the fork
这里做的事就叫做「join」，前面的叫做「fork」
And then it waits for all the threads to finish
管理线程等待所有的工作线程完成
By doing a join okay so this is called
通过调用 pthread_join
This is called the fork and this is called the join
前面做的事 fork，这里做的事 ßßßßjoin
And only when all of the threads have finished
因为只有当所有工作线程都完成时
Can it go and do the next do the next phase
才可以去做下一阶段的工作
Okay so this model is really important in things like scientific computing where
好的，这个模型在科学计算等方面非常重要
You might...you're simulating some domain,you're simulating nature
在一些领域，你可能需要做一些仿真，比如仿真自然界的一些现象
So you represent that as some domain like maybe you're simulating
你可能需要对
How heat flows over a plate you know metal plate
热量流过金属板的现象进行仿真
And so you might have these workers
所以你可能需要创建一些工作线程
You might partition the domain amongst a set of those workers
每个工作线程只负责金属板的一个区域的仿真
And then each one of these phases is a time step
然后，每一阶段代表一个时间点
And then so once all the workers have finished a time step then they can advance to the next time step
所以，只有所有的工作线程完成了一个时间点，才可以进入到下一个时间点
And so sorry I don't know why,I didn't think of it
对不起，我不知道为什么上次课我没想到这个例子
That's a that's an important reason why you'd want this
所以，这就是我们为什么要使用可结合的线程
Okay so we saw
好的
We've seen the threaded programs are nice
我们已经看到了线程程序好的方面
Because you they you can share all the global variables
使用线程的并发可以共享所有全局变量
But this the sharing can have unintended consequences
但这种共享可能会产生意外的结果
So somehow we need a mechanism where we can control
所以我们需要一种机制，可以控制
How the flows of each individual thread are interleaved
线程交错的顺序（进程调度的顺序）
So that bad things don't happen when we share data structures
只有这样，当我们共享数据结构时，才不会发生坏事
Okay so this this process of controlling the interleaving is called synchronization
好的，控制进程交错的过程称为同步
So we're going to look at techniques that you can use to write correct threaded programs by properly synchronizing them
我们将学习线程同步的一些技术，使用它们可以编写出正确的线程程序
Now first though we need to have a clear idea
现在首先我们需要知道的是
So sharing is the issue right if we have threads that aren't sharing any resources
只有资源共享会产生同步问题，如果我们的线程没有共享任何资源
Then there's no problem right
就没有同步问题
That we saw this when we looked at it processes there's no shared data structures with processes
如果一个进程没有共享任何数据结构
So we process these just run independently we don't really care how they're interleaved note no worries okay
这些线程是独立运行的，线程如何交错都不会有问题，我们不需要担心
But as soon as they introduce sharing then we have to be careful
但是一旦线程之间共享资源，我们就必须小心
Okay so to understand how to synchronize threads we first need to have a clear idea
好，了解线程同步之前，我们首先需要
Of what we mean by sharing in in threaded C programs
知道什么是线程中的资源共享
So the answer is not as simple as global variables are shared and stack variables are not shared
答案并不是像「全局变量是共享的，栈变量是不共享的」这样简单
Okay so with instead what we x is shared
如果资源 x 是共享的
If only multiple threads reference some instance so that that variable x
当且仅当有多个线程引用资源 x 的某个实例
All right so if only one thread is accessing a particular variable
好吧，如果只有一个线程访问特定变量
Then it's not shared
这个变量没有被共享
Okay so...
然后...
In order to know exactly what we mean by shared we need to answer three questions
为了确切地知道共享的含义，我们需要回答三个问题
Okay first what is the memory model for threads
首先是线程的内存模型是什么
Okay second how are instances of variables mapped to memory
第二，变量实例如何映射到内存
And then third how many threads might be referencing those the instances of those variables
第三个，有多少线程引用这些实例
Okay so we'll look at each of those now in turn each of those three questions
好的，我们现在依次来解决这三个问题
Okay so first is that the memory model
首先是内存模型
The conceptual model is a little bit different from the operational model the way it really works
概念模型与真实系统略有不同
Okay so conceptually
从概念上讲
We have multiple threads that run in the context of a single process
我们有多个线程在单个进程的上下文中运行
Okay and some of that context is shared and some of its not shared
有些进程上下文是共享的，有些不是共享的
So each thread has its own separate thread id,stack,stack pointer,program counter,condition codes,general-purpose registers
每个线程都有自己独立的线程 id，栈，栈指针，程序计数器，条件码，通用目的的寄存器值
And then they all share the remaining process context which is data structures that the kernel maintains
然后线程共享剩余的进程上下文，进程上下文由内核维护
For the threads the virtual data structures to support the virtual memory system open files install signal handlers and so forth
如虚拟内存系统中的数据结构，打开的文件描述符，信号处理程序等等
So that's the conceptual model and that if that were really enforced
这是概念模型，如果实际的系统是这样实现的话
It would be nice it would make things simpler for us
那很好，因为它会让事情变的更简单
But unfortunately in real life this model is not strictly enforced
但不幸的是，在实际的系统中，并没有严格按照这种模式实现
Now although register values are really separate right the kernel maintains separate context for all the registers
实际上，虽然寄存器值是独立的，内核为所有寄存器维护单独的上下文
So that part is good
这部分是好的
But since the threads share the address space,a thread can access the the memory the stack
但由于线程共享地址空间，因此线程可以访问所有的栈
One thread can access the stack of an another thread
一个线程可以访问另一个线程的栈
Okay so although conceptually these stacks are separate and distinct and in private they're really not
虽然从概念上讲这些栈是独立的，但实际并非如此
And so this can create some problems
这可能会产生一些问题
So here's an example of that we'll come back to later
这是一个例子，我们会看到
Of how this one thread can access the stack of another thread
一个线程如何访问另一个线程的栈
So here we're defining a global variable called pointer
所以这里我们定义一个名为 ptr 的全局变量
Which is a char **
类型为 char **
And then in the main routine on were declaring a local variable called messages which contains
然后在主线程中声明一个名为 msgs 的局部变量
It's a two element array which contains a couple strings
msgs 是一个字符串数组，包含两个字符串
Which these will be printed out by the threads that we're going to create
我们要创建两个线程来打印这两个字符串
And then we assign the global pointer to the address of the array messages
然后我们让 「ptr = msgs」
Okay so now pointer points to messages
现在，ptr 指向了 msgs
And then we create in a loop we create two threads
然后我们循环创建两个线程
Each of which executes this routine called thread
每个线程执行一个名为 thread 的函数
And and we're passing an argument
并且我们传递一个参数给 thread 函数
So the Pthreads will assign a thread id but in this case we're going to assign our own local thread id
pthread_create 将分配一个线程 ID，这里我们赋值给 tid
By passing this loop index
然后我们把循环索引 i 作为参数传递给 thread 函数
Okay so this is an example we talked about this last time
好的，这和我们上次讲的例子一样
It's kind of...it's this is perfectly okay there's no race
这有点奇怪，但这样做是没问题的，不会产生竞争
But it's a little weird because we're going to take this index i and cast it to a generic pointer
但它有点奇怪，因为我们把索引 i 强制转换成了一个「void *」类型
Okay and then after we create these threads then we'll exit the main thread
然后在创建这些线程之后，我们退出主线程
Now each the thread routine dereferences its argument to get the local the local thread id
每个线程将参数强制转换成 long 类型，得到线程 id
And then it declares a static variable count
然后它声明了一个静态变量 cnt
That we're going to use to count how many times this thread routine is called inside of a thread
我们用 cnt 来统计线程被调用的次数
And then it just prints a simple message from identifying that giving the local thread id
然后它只是简单的根据 myid
And then the message indexed by myid
打印 msgs 中的字符串
So pointer points to messages
因为 ptr 指向 msgs
So thread zero will print "hello from foo"
所以线程零将打印「hello from foo」
And thread 1 will print "hello from bar"
并且线程 1 将打印「hello from bar」
And then we increment the pre increment the counter variable
然后我们把 cnt 的值 +1
Okay so
然后
Although it doesn't you would it looks like we're accessing this global variable pointer
这里看上去我们访问的是一个全局的指针变量 ptr
But since that was assigned to be the address of the local variable on the main thread stack
但是因为 ptr 指向了 msgs，msgs 是存储在主线程栈上的一个局部变量
We've got this these peer threads accessing local variables on the main thread stack okay
所以我们这里访问了主线程栈上的局部变量
So that I just this is not it you never want to do this as a very bad practice
这种做法不好，在实际编程中最好不要这样做
But I...it's a kind of thing that can happen sometimes
但有时候我们也会这样做，但我们还没有意识到
By accident you know if you forget that pointer actually was assigned to you know some stack address
比如你忘记了 ptr 实际上指向了一个栈地址
Okay so the second question that is how do we map variable instances to memory
好的，第二个问题是我们如何将变量实例映射到内存
Now we looked at this when we studied linking
讲链接那节课时，我们学过了这个
But let's just review this quickly again to make sure that it's clear to you
让我们快速回顾一下
So global variables are variables that are referenced outside of a function
全局变量是定义在函数外的变量
And virtual memory the linker when it does symbol resolution make sure that
链接器在进行符号解析时确保
There's exactly one instance of every global variable in virtual memory
虚拟内存中的每个全局变量都只有一个实例
Now local variables are declared on the stack inside of a function
局部变量在函数的内部声明，在栈上分配内存
Without the static attribute
如果该局部变量没有使用 static 修饰
And so in this case each the stack for each thread will contain one instance of that local variable
因此，在这种情况下，每个线程的栈上将包含该局部变量的一个实例
Now
嗯
If variables are declared inside of a function with the static attribute
如果变量在函数内部声明且用 static 修饰
Then the scope of that variable is limited to that function meaning no other function can access it
然后该变量的范围仅限于该函数，即没有其他函数可以访问它
But that static variable is stored along with all the other local variables
但是，该静态变量与所有其他全局（原文是局部）变量存储在一起
So there's any static variable declared inside of a function has exactly one instance in memory
因此，在函数内部声明的任何静态变量在内存中只有一个实例
And if you were to have say multiple functions that declared (the same) a static variable with the same name
如果多个函数声明一个具有相同名称的静态变量
The compiler would disambiguate those somehow
编译器会以某种方式消除歧义
It would append some kind of unique
它会附加某种唯一的标识
It would somehow make that name unique
或它会以某种方式使这个变量名独一无二
Okay so what recall how all these different types of variable instances are mapped into memory
那么回想一下所有这些不同类型的变量实例是如何映射到内存的
Okay pointer is a global variable
ptr 是一个全局变量
So there's one instance of pointer in the address space
所以地址空间中有一个 ptr 的实例
And it's stored in the data segment
它存储在数据段中
i and messages are examples of local variables to main
i 和 msgs 是主线程上的局部变量
So there's one instance of these stored on the stack of main stack
所以主线程的栈上存储这些变量的实例
And we'll denote those with this notation we'll say variable i
我们用下面这种方式来表示
i.m means variable i is stored on main stack
i.m 表示变量 i 存储在主线程的栈上
And messages is stored on the stack of main
msgs.m 表示 msgs 存储在主线程的栈上
Okay now myid is a local variable defined in this thread routine
myid 是在这个线程函数中定义的局部变量
And so there's actually since there's two of these threads
实际上，因为有两个这样的线程
There's there's now there are in memory there's there's two instances of myid one for each stack
所有有两个 myid 的实例，一个线程有一个
Okay associated with the stack associated with each thread
因为每个线程都有一个相关联的栈
So myid.p0 is stored on peer thread 0's stack
所以，myid.p0 表示存储在线程 0 的栈上的 mypid 实例
And myid.p1 is stored on peer thread 1's stack
myid.p1 表示存储在线程 1 的栈上的 myid 实例
Ok and now this counter variable the static counter variable has just exactly one instance in virtual memory
好了，静态变量 cnt 在虚拟内存中只有一个实例
And it sits in the data segment along with the other global variables like like pointer
它和其他全局变量一样位于数据段中，如 ptr
Okay now so the question is
好的，现在问题是
Which of these variables are shared and which are not
哪些变量是共享的，哪些不是
Okay so we can
好的
Remember what we said is it's shared if more than one thread is accessing an instance of that variable
根据定义，如果有多个线程正在访问该变量的实例，我们说该变量是共享的
Okay so let's just list all the different variables
让我们列出所有不同的变量
And then let's look at each of these threads and see if it's referenced by that thread
然后看看这些变量都被哪些线程引用
Okay so what about,what about pointer
从 ptr 开始
Right there's just it's referenced by the main thread right
ptr 被主线程引用
And what about peer threads zero
ptr 被线程 0 引用吗？
Yeah it's referenced by peer thread zero right here
对，它被线程 0 引用
Right here
就在这儿（printf语句中）
And similarly for peer thread one
同样，线程一也引用了 ptr
Okay so pointer is referenced by all three threads
好的，所以三个线程都引用了 ptr
Now what about count
那 cnt 的情况呢？
Counts not referenced by the main thread
cnt 未被主线程引用
But it is referenced by the two peer threads
但它被线程 0 和线程 1 引用
Now what about i in main
主线程中的变量 i 的情况呢
That's referenced by main of course
当然，i 被主线程引用
But not by but not by either of the two threads
但线程 0 和线程 1 都没有引用i
Now we're about messages, the messages array
我们现在来看 msgs
Okay so that's accessed by main
它们被主线程引用
And indirectly through pointer
并通过 ptr
It's referenced by each of these two peer threads
被线程 0 和线程 1 引用
Now what about myid defined in peer thread zero
线程零中定义的 myid 的情况呢
Okay so that's referenced that's a local variable
它是一个局部变量
So it's only referenced by peer thread zero right it's not referenced by either the other threads
所以它只被对程零引用，没有被其他线程引用
And similarly for myid and in peer threat one
线程1中的 mypid 也是类似的
Okay so given that definition then
那么根据共享的定义
Which of these variables is shared
这些变量中的哪些是共享的
So it's really straightforward with yeah
这真的很直白
Okay so the question is discount count as a share variable and answer is yes
变量 cnt 肯定是共享的
Because it's declared static
因为它被定义为静态的
It's there's one instance of it in virtual memory
它在虚拟内存中的只有一个实例
And each of the threads references that instance
且线程 0 和线程 1 都引用该实例
Okay so it's shared,it's really like a global variable
所以它是共享的，它真的像一个全局变量
It's just a scope is limited to the...
但它共享的范围只限于该函数
It stored the same way a global variable is but its scope is limited to the function that it's defined in
它以与全局变量相同的方式存储，但其范围仅限于其定义的函数
Okay so to determine if each one of these is whether
为了确定这些变量中
Which of these variables are shared in which one's not we just
哪些变量是共享的，哪些不是共享的
We just look go across and for any variable with its shared by more than,more than one thread then it's shared
我们只需要看这个变量是否被多个线程引用，如果是，则该变量是共享的
So pointer shared
所以 ptr 是共享的
So pointer is shared count is not shared
所以 ptr 是共享的，cnt 不是共享的
Oh no count is shared because it's it's referenced by peer thread zero and peer thread one
抱歉，cnt 是共享的，因为它被线程 0 和线程 1 引用
I's not shared because it's only referenced by main
i 不是共享的，因为它仅被主线程引用
So
所以
Messages is access referenced by all three threads so it's shared
msgs 被三个线程引用，因此 msgs 是共享的
But myid is not shared because it's only referenced by exactly one thread
但 myid 没有共享，因为它只被一个线程引用
Okay so pointer count and messages are the shared variables in this program and the others are not share
好的，所以这个程序中 ptr，msgs，cnt 是共享的，其他的变量是不共享的
Yes
请讲
[student speaking]
[学生提问]
So if you declared my ideas static
如果把 myid 定义为静态变量
With the second process of overridden it yeah that would be a race
第二个线程会改变 myid 的值，这里产生了竞争
Okay so that would...we just depend on which thread executed first
所以运行的结果取决于哪个线程先执行
So you would really wouldn't want to do that
所以在实际的代码中不要这样做
Okay so we have a very clear notion now of what we mean by sharing
好的，现在我们对共享有了一个非常明确的认识
So these being able to share variables like this in this ways is very handy
以这种方式共享变量是非常方便的
But you can run into some really nasty problems
但是你可能遇到一些非常讨厌的问题
That are very surprising,so let me show you an example
这些问题可能令人惊讶，让我给你举个例子
This is a program
这是一个程序
Called bad count so obviously there's something wrong with this I'm giving you a little clue
这个程序被称为 bad count，取这个名字暗示这个程序在计数上会出错
But what we want to do is we want to create a bunch of threads or a number of threads
我们想要做的是创建多个线程
And each of those threads will increment a global variable called count
每个线程都会增加全局变量 cnt 的值
Some number of times the same number of times
并且增加的次数相等
Okay so we pass in the number of iterations as the first argument
好的，我们将迭代次数作为第一个参数传递给 thread 函数
And here's our well here's our global globally shared variable
这里是我们的全局共享变量 cnt
And you remember what volatile means
你还记得 volatile 关键字的含义吗
Everybody remember what that means
你们都记得这个关键字的含义吗
So what is volatile,what is volatile tell the compiler
什么是 volatile，volatile 有什么作用？
Yes
请讲
[student speaking]
[学生回答]
It actually you're on in the right direction actually tells,it tells the compiler never to put that variable in a register
你回答的方向是正确的，实际上，volatile 告诉编译器永远不要把该变量放在寄存器中
Okay so it always read that value from memory or store it to memory and
所以，volatile 修饰的变量总是从内存中读取，修改后又存储到内存中
You do that because of exactly the kind of possibility that you mentioned
使用 volatile 关键字是因为你提到的那种可能性
So in this case we have
我们回来看看我们的程序
We create two threads by with two distinct calls to two pthread create
我们调用了两次 pthread_create 函数，创建了两个线程
Each of these threads will run the the thread routine called thread
每个线程都将执行名为 thread 的函数
And it will pass and as an argument the address of the number of iterations that it should
并将 niters 的地址作为参数传递给了 thread 函数
That it should iterate
作为 thread 函数中循环的迭代次数
Now you remember when we were looking when we were passing connected file descriptors
现在你还记得当我们传递连接文件描述符的时候
If we pass an address that was a race
如果我们传递的是一个地址，那将会产生竞争
Okay but in this case there's no race this is fine
但是在这种情况下没有出现竞争的情况，这是正确的
It's fine just to pass the address of number of iterations
传递迭代次数的参数的地址是没问题的
So why is it okay in this case but it wasn't okay when we were passing the connected file descriptor
那么为什么在这种情况下它没问题，但是当我们传递文件描述符给线程时并不合适
That we got from acceptant to our thread routine
调用 accept 得到的文件描述符
Yes
请讲
Exactly because the thread doesn't modify the value
对，答案就是这里线程不会修改该迭代次数的值
And that the problem we had before was that our main thread was modifying that connected descriptor on the next call to accept
而在上一个例子中，当主线程调用 accept 函数时，会修改文件描述符
But here it's just a read-only variable so we're okay
但这里它只是一个只读变量，所以这里是没问题的
But you see the how tricky the reasoning can get right there's
你会发现要判断是否有竞争是比较棘手的
You can't do pattern matching to determine whether you've got races or not races
因为你无法通过模式匹配来确定是否有竞争
Right so you can't just say well
你不能简单的说
It's always bad to pass the address of some variable to a thread routine
将某个变量的地址传递给线程总是出现竞争
Okay because it's not it just depends on the context
但有时候不会，这取决于上下文
Okay so in this case we're passing the number of iterations and to each thread and
好的，在这种情况下，我们将迭代次数传递给每个线程
Then we're waiting for each of those threads to finish
然后我们等待每个线程完成
So this is an example of why you need why you might want to have a non detached thread
所以这是一个为什么你需要使用非分离线程的例子
Because you can't
因为你需要等待线程完成
We want when we check when we check the value of count
在检查 cnt 的值的时候
We have to make sure that every thread is finished before we check whether we got the right value or not
我们必须确保每个线程都已完成
Okay so we wait for each thread to finish
好的，我们等待每个线程完成
And now since we've created two threads each of which is incrementing count editors time
现在，因为我们已经创建了两个线程，每个线程都会让 cnt 的值增加 nithers 次
We expect count to be equal to two times and niters
所以最后 cnt 的应该为 niters 的两倍
And if it's not we print my favorite error message
如果不是，打印错误消息
Otherwise we with the value of count,otherwise we print OK also with the value of count
如果相值，我们也会打印 OK，然后打印 cnt 的值
Okay so now what's going on in the thread routine
好的，现在看看线程中执行了什么
Very simple
很简单
It dereferences the argument that was passed in and stores it in the local copy of entities
首先，它解指针，然后把值保存在一个本地变量中
And then it loop senators time
然后循环 niters 次
In can increments count each time
每次将 cnt 的值增加 1
So and then returns
然后返回
So this is very innocuous what could go wrong
这看上去是对的，到底哪里会出错呢
And since this is threading,since this is concurrent concurrent programming,especially since it's threaded programming
因为这里使用了线程，因为这是并发编程，是基于线程的并发编程
What there's the odd lots of subtle things can go wrong
很多小事都会导致结果出错
So it turns out this program has a really serious bug
实际上，这个程序有一个非常严重的 bug
Okay because when we run it
因为当我们运行它
When we run it on a Linux box
当我们在 Linux 机器上运行它时
Sometimes if we call it with an argument of ten thousand
如果执行这个程序，并且传入一个参数 10000
Sometimes we get the correct answer 2*10,000 or 20,000
有时我们得到 2 * 10,000，即 20,000 的正确答案
But then the next time we run it
但是下次我们运行它
We get some weird number 13051
我们得到一些奇怪的数字 13051
Completely wrong
完全错了
And so what the hack is going on here
那么这里发生了什么
Okay so to understand that we have to look at the assembly language
好的，要理解为什么会出现这个结果，我们必须查看汇编语言
For this counter loop so that
循环部分对应的汇编代码如下
We want to...we need to look at the the assembly language for this counter loop in the thread routine
我们只需要检查循环这一部分的汇编代码
So we'll break it up into three chunks that
所以我们将它分成三个块
The first chunk is sort of getting ready for the loop
第一个块是为循环做好准备
We'll call that the head and we'll denote it as H(i)  for thread i
我们称之为 Head，线程 i Head 块记为 H(i)
And then we'll isolate on these three instructions that are directly related to incrementing count
然后我们将与 cnt++ 直接相关的指令分为几个部分
Okay so you see the first instruction moves
第一条指令是 mov 指令
It loads the global of the value and global variable count into register %rdx
它将 cnt 的值加载到寄存器 ％rdx 中
So will denote that as L(i)
我们将其表示为 L(i)
Next it increments %rdx
下一条指令增加 ％rdx 的值
And we'll denote that U(i) for update so it updates %rdx
这是更新 ％rdx，我们将其表示为 U(i)
And then it stores the value the updated value of %rdx into count
然后下一条指令将 ％rdx 的更新值存储到 cnt 中
Okay so into the location associated with the global variable count
也就是更新 cnt 的内存地址上的内容
And
然后
And then the rest of...the rest of this loop is getting ready for the to do the next iteration
这个循环的其余部分的功能是，为下一次迭代做好准备
It's not directly related to incrementing count
它与 cnt 的值没有直接关系
So we'll just sort of group this all together and refer to it as T(i) for tail
我们将其组合为一块，称为尾部，记为 T(i)
Okay
好的
Now let's look at...let's look at...
让我们来看......
How this how these two threads might be executed
这两个线程可能的执行顺序
And remember in general we can't assume that there's any specific interleaving
记住，一般来说，我们不能假设任何特定的顺序
So any interleaving of these two threads is possible
因此，这两个线程的任何交错都是可能的
No matter how remote it might seem
无论它看起来多么遥远（一个线程运行了很久，另一个线程才运行）
So let's look at one example let's say we're executing on a single core
让我们看一个例子，假设我们在一个单核的计算机上执行
So we're only going to do one instruction at a time
所以我们一次只会执行一条指令
And
然后
In this column will show which thread is executing so either thread 1 or thread 2
在此列中显示正在执行的线程，线程 1 或线程 2
And then we'll to know which instruction in that thread is executing
这一列表示该线程中的哪条指令正在执行
Either H,L,U,S or T
H，L，U，S 或 T
And then this column shows the value of %rdx for thread number 1
然后此列显示线程 1 的 ％rdx 的值
And this column shows the value of %rdx for thread number 2
此列显示线程 2 的 ％rdx 值
Right since that the kernel keeps separate copies of all the general-purpose registers the for each thread these can be different
因为内核为每个线程都维护了一个所有通用寄存器的副本，相当于每个线程都有独立的寄存器
Okay and then this last column shows the value of count in memory
好的，然后最后一列显示内存中 cnt 的值
So let's start executing
我们开始执行代码
So initially count is equal to 0
最初 cnt 等于 0
And thread one gets the kernel schedules thread 1
然后内核调度线程 1
So it executes say H(1) that has no impact on count
线程 1 执行 H(1)，对 cnt 没有影响
Then thread 1 loads the value of count into its copy of %rdx
然后，线程 1 将 cnt 的值加载到其 ％rdx 的副本中
Updates it
更新它
So now %rdx is equal to 1 and then stores that value in %rdx back to count so now count is equal to 1
所以现在 ％rdx 等于 1，然后将 ％rdx 中的值更新到 cnt，所以现在 cnt 等于 1
Now at this point the kernel decides to schedule thread 2
此时内核决定调度线程 2
So thread 2 begins executing and when it begins executing value of count is 1
因此线程 2 开始执行，当它开始执行时，cnt 的值为 1
So it executes H(i)
然后线程 2 执行 H(i)
Then it loads count into thread 2 copy of %rdx
然后它将 cnt 加载到线程 2 的 ％rdx 副本中
So now %rdx equals 1,updates it,now it's equal to 2
所以现在 ％rdx 等于 1，更新它，现在 cnt 等于 2
And then stores that value back to count
然后将寄存器的值更新到 cnt
The kernel then decides oh and then it finishes executing the tail instruction
然后线程 2 执行 T(i)
And let's say we're just doing one iteration of this
我们只是对此进行了一次迭代
And then at this point the kernel decides to schedule thread 1 since thread 2 is finished so
然后在这一点上，内核决定调度线程 1，因为线程 2 已完成
Thread 1 executes the remaining statement that it has to execute
线程 1 执行必须执行的剩余语句
And at this point both threads have finished
此时两个线程都已完成
And count is equal to 2 which is the value we would expect
而 cnt 等于 2，这是我们期望的值
Ok so this so this is ok
好的，所以运行的结果是正确的
And notice how...so this is actually this is an inner leaving that works
实际上，这只是线程交错的其中一种情况
Ok we get the correct value
这次我们得到的结果是正确的
And notice how I...
注意
I grouped the 3 instructions that are actually involved in updating count together
我实际上将参与更新 cnt 的 3 条指令放在了一起
And it will call that,we'll call those 3 instructions a critical section and I've color-coded them
我们将这 3 条指令称为临界区，并使用了不同颜色进行区分
So you can easily keep track of them
因此，你可以轻松的找到它们
Alright let's look...now let's look at another another interleaving which is feasible right
现在让我们看看另一个可能的交错
But in this case it results in the wrong value
但在这种情况下，它会导致错误的结果
Ok so here we start with thread 1 again
好的，我们再次从线程1开始
It loads it's the value of count into its copy of %rdx updates it
它将 cnt 的值加载到 ％rdx 的副本中，然后更新它
But then before it can store it
但在更新值写回到内存之前
The kernel decides to schedule thread 2
内核决定调度线程 2
So thread 2 begins x executing
所以线程 2 开始执行
It loads count into its copy of %rdx too
它也会将 cnt 加载到线程 2 的 ％rdx 的副本中
And notice count is still 0 right it's 1
注意到，此时内存中的 cnt 是 0，但是在这里（鼠标指的地方）它是 1
In the value of in thread 1 in the %rdx
也就是在线程 1 的 %rdx 的副本中的值是 1
The copy of %rdx and thread 1 but it hasn't been updated in memory so
但线程 1 中的 %rdx 的值没有更新到内存中
When thread 2 loads its value of count
当线程 2 加载其 cnt 值时
Now it's copy and %rdx is 0
cnt 为 0，所以线程 2 的 ％rdx 副本为 0
Now at this point the kernel reschedules thread 1 to execute so thread 1 does it store
现在，此时内核重新安排线程 1 执行，因此线程 1 会存储它
Of its copy of %rdx into count
将 ％rdx 的副本值更新到 cnt 中
And then finishes executing it the tail instruction
然后完成尾部指令的执行
The kernel reschedules thread 2 which picks up where it left off it updates
内核重新调度线程 2，它从它停止的地方开始执行
Its copy of count
更新 %rdx 中的值
So now %rdx goes from 0 to 1
所以现在 ％rdx 从 0 变为 1
And then it stores that value into count
然后它将该值更新到 cnt 中
So all we've done is we've overwritten count out a value 1
这一步所做的就是将 cnt 的值更新为 1
And we've overwritten it with a value of 1
我们让 cnt 的值为 1
So when we finish execution of these two threads count has the wrong value
所以当我们完成这两个线程的执行时，cnt 有错误的值
Okay in the
好的
That then the general like,the general thing to notice is you see how these critical sections have been interleaved
我们要关注临界区的交错情况
Right in this case
就在这种情况下
This is the first the critical section for thread 1 executed before the critical section for thread 2
这里线程 2 执行临界区代码时，线程 1 的临界区代码已经执行完毕了，没有交错
Okay but in this case the two critical sections interleaved okay
但是第二个例子中，两个临界区交错了
So let's see another example of that
让我们看看另一个例子
So here you can see that these are interleaved so
这里它们的临界区是交错的
Probably suggest there might be a problem.Yes!
这种交错方式可能也会产生错误的结果 请讲
[student speaking]
[学生提问]
So I'm sorry excuse me
对不起，我没听清楚
[student speaking]
[学生提问]
Well no okay so the question is would would
他的问题是
i or count
i 还是 cnt
If we...okay it is defined as volatile
cnt 被定义为 volatile
Yeah so that that's why...I mean there's actually and the compiler could have compiled this code in different ways right
我的意思是，实际上，编译器可以用不同的方式编译这段代码
There is actually an increment instruction that you will increment a variable in memory
实际上有一个增量指令，这个指令可以让内存中的变量的值增加
So you could have done
所以
The compiler could have generated this
编译器可能生成这 3 条指令
This 3 instruction sequence is one instruction and then we wouldn't have this problem
也可能把这 3 个指令序列合并为一条指令，如果编译为一条指令，那这个程序就没有问题
But the problem is that
但问题是
It's loading into register then incrementing and then saving
这里 cnt 会加载到寄存器，然后在寄存器递增，然后保存到内存
So that the problem comes about because
因此，问题就出现了
We can
嗯
This thread can be interrupted before it finishes this three-step sequence
在加载、更新、写回的过程中
This load modify store sequence
线程可能被中断
Yes
请讲
[student speaking]
[学生提问]
It would wait yeah so it that's right yeah I guess I wasn't clear it
我想我没有把 volatile 关键字讲清楚
It prevents it from being stored permanently in a register right so
volatile 可以防止变量永久存储在寄存器中（如循环执行完了再将 cnt 的值写回）
It may have to be loaded into a register but then it'll be written back
volatile 修饰的变量可以被加载到寄存器中，但紧接着该变量的值要被写回到内存
Okay whereas the the compiler would have the option like we've seen it with local variables
编译器在处理语句的时候有多种选择，如对于局部变量来说
Right the compiler just it never allocates stack space
编译器永远不会为其分配栈空间
It just keeps that local variable in a register all the time
它将局部变量保存在寄存器中
Okay so this prevent the volatile attribute prevents the compiler from doing that
volatile 属性可以阻止编译器这样做
Okay so let's look at another example
好的，让我们看看另一个例子
So here thread 1 starts
首先线程 1 开始执行
It loads count into %rdx
它将 cnt 加载到 ％rdx
Then thread 2 starts
然后线程 2 开始执行
And it loads a count which is still 0 into %rdx(2)
此时 cnt 的值仍然为 0，线程 2 将其加载到 %rdx 中
Updates it and then stores it so now count equal to 1
更新它然后写回到内存，所以现在 cnt 等于 1
When thread 1 resumes it updates its value of count and %rdx and stores that back to count
然后线程 1 恢复执行，它会更新 ％rdx 的值并将其更新到内存，更新 cnt 的值
And so again we have the same problem
所以我们再次遇到和上次一样的问题
Okay so the...
好的，所以......
The problem here is that we're interleaving these these critical sections
这里的问题是我们交错了临界区
And you can understand why this is bad
你现在应该可以理解为什么这个程序有问题
With a nice or graphical technique called a progress graph
现在我们使用进度图来表示程序的执行过程
So in a progress graph
在进度图中
If we have n threads it's an n dimensional cartesian grid
如果我们有 n 个线程，它就是一个 n 维笛卡尔网格
That characterizes the execution state space of a concurrent threaded program
进度图刻画了线程程序执行的状态空间
So in this case each here we have two threads
在我们讲的例子中，我们有两个线程
So it's a 2d coordinate system
所以它是一个二维坐标系
So each axis represents the progress the execution progress of some threads
因此每个轴代表一个线程的执行进度
So the x axis here is thread 1
这里的 x 轴是线程 1 的执行进度
And the y axis corresponds to thread 2
y 轴对应于线程 2 的执行进度
And then each one of these edges corresponds to the execution of an instruction
然后，每一条边对应于一条指令的执行
Ok so we start out in an initial state
好的，我们从初始状态开始
And then the first thing we execute is H(1)
然后我们执行 H(1)
So that's represented by this ACK here
对应于这一条边
So this position this point right here represents the state where
所以这个点代表的状态是
We've executed H,we finished executing H(1) in thread 1
在线程 1 中已经完成了 H(1) 的执行
But we haven't yet executed any instructions in thread 2
但是我们还没有执行线程 2 中的任何指令
Ok so in general each one of these points represents
好的，所以这里的每一个点都代表
Sort of the current progress of the program or the execution state
程序当前的执行状态
So for example this state right here represents the state where thread 1
例如 PPT 上红色的这个点，代表了
Has completed a completed L1
线程 1 已经完成了 L(1)
And thread 2 is completed S(2)
线程 2 完成 S(2)
And now the execution of a program is modeled as a transition from one state to the other
现在，程序的执行可以表示为从一个状态到另一个状态的转移
And there's some,so from this and there's constraints on how
需要注意的一点，这里
On how these states can advance so
对状态的转移有一些限制
From this state(L1, S2)
从这个状态（L1，S2）
Obviously time can't go backwards right so we can't go backwards like in this direction to the left and we can't go down
因为时间不能倒退，所以我们不能回到左边的状态，也不能回到下边的状态
Okay so we can only go to the right and up
所以我们只能向右或向上走
And since we're assuming that each instruction executes
这里我们还假设
There's only one instruction executing at a time
一次只执行一条指令
We can't go diagonally that would be two instructions
所以我们不能走对角线，因为这样同时执行了两条指令
All right so from (L1,S2)
好的，从（L1，S2）
The next execution state is either
下一个执行状态是
Here if thread one execute or here if thread of thread to execute
右边这个点，代表线程 1 执行，或者上面这个点，代表线程 2 执行
Okay so you can put all these together to form a trajectory
好的，你可以把所有点放在一起形成一个轨迹
Which characterizes one execution of the program
这个轨迹表示了程序的一次执行
Right and any feasible set of transitions from one state to the next corresponds to a feasible trajectory
且这个轨迹中只含有可行的状态转换，即向右或向上
So for example H(1),L(1),U(1),H(2),L(2),S(1),T(1),U(2),S(2),T(2)
如 H(1),L(1),U(1),H(2),L(2),S(1),T(1),U(2),S(2),T(2)
That's a feasible
那是可行的
That's a feasible trajectory
这是一条可行的轨迹
And it's one possible it represents one possible execution or so one set of inter leavings for this program
并且它代表一个线程程序可能的执行过程，即线程一个可能的交错顺序
Now these L these three instructions L,U and S that operate on that manipulate count
L、U、S 这三个指令会对 cnt 进行操作
Form what we call a critical section with respect to count
这三个指令被称为临界区
And the idea is that instructions inside
要使这个程序得到正确结果的一个想法是
These critical sections this with receivership with respect to the same global variable shouldn't be interleaved
这些对全局变量 cnt 进行操作的临界区不应该被交错
So we can capture this geometrically by taking the intersection of these critical sections
两个临界区的交集形成的状态空间称为
To form what we call an unsafe region
不安全区
So in this an unsafe region is...
不安全区是......
The points within an unsafe region are those points in an execution where the critical sections are being or interleaved
不安全区包含那些会使临界区交错的点
Okay so for this particular example there's four points within the unsafe region
好的，在这个例子中，不安全区内有四个点
And if a trajectory ever touches one of those points
如果一个轨迹经过了其中一个点
Then we've interleaved critical section and we're going to get the wrong answer
然后我们交错了临界区，我们将得到错误的答案
Okay so the idea is to try to stay out of these unsafe regions
好的，所以我们应该远离不安全区
And if we do we say that trajectory is safe so
如果轨迹没有经过不安全区，我们说轨迹是安全的
Here's an example of a trajectory that's safe
这是一个安全的轨迹示例
Now this is okay,right this point right here is not in the unsafe region
当前这个点是可以经过的，因为它不在不安全区内
Because we haven't executed we only executed H(1) here
因为这里线程 1 只执行了 H(1)
Remember a point corresponds to
记住每个点的含义
And it's the instruction that we've completed that instruction
每个点对应一条指令的完成
So then
那么
So here we're skirting the unsafe region
所以我们在这里避开不安全区
But it's still okay,so this is a safe trajectory we'll get the right answer for this one
所以这是一个安全的轨迹，我们将得到正确的答案
However
然而
This trajectory is unsafe because it
这条轨迹是不安全的，因为
It enters the unsafe region at this point here
它进入不安全区
And even though it quickly exited the there's an interleaving there that creates a potential for a correct answer
即使它很快就会退出，但那里的交错会使得答案发送错误
Okay so the question is how do we guarantee a safe trajectory
好，现在的问题是我们如何保证安全的轨迹
And this is the this is what we call synchronization
也就是我们所说的同步
So somehow we want to sort of configure the kernel
我们想以某种方式配置内核
So that'll never schedule an unsafe trajectory
使得内核永远不会调度不安全的轨迹
So how do we do that
那我们该怎么做呢
So somehow
嗯
We we have to synchronize the execution of those threads
我们必须同步这些线程的执行
And another way to think of this is that we need to guarantee mutually exclusive access to the critical sections
但从另外一个角度讲，我们只需要保证对临界区的互斥访问
All right so once the kernel begins,once the thread starts executing the first instruction is critical section
一旦一个线程开始执行临界区的第一条指令
We don't want it to be interrupted by another thread that has a similar critical section
我们不希望它被另一个具有相同临界区的线程打断
Okay we don't want it to be interrupted
好的，我们不希望它被打断
We don't want...one critical section with respect to a certain global variable
例如，一个对应于某个全局变量的临界区
To be interrupted by another thread that has all right that's currently within that same critical section okay
不能被执行同样的临界区的另一个线程打断
Sorry yes question
请讲
[student speaking]
学生提问
Okay so the question is how likely is it that you get a correct trajectory
他的问题是，在一次程序的执行中，获得正确轨迹的可能性有多大
And it happens right you can run it sometimes you do
你运行这个程序时
It just depends usually it's wrong sometimes it's right
通常结果是错误的，但有时结果是正确的
And it just depends on how the kernel scheduled it and you can't assume any particular scheduling
程序的结果只取决于内核如何调度它，并且你不能假设任何特定的调度
Right so if you say, if you want to claim that you would never get the right answer
你可以假设程序输出的答案永远是错的
Then you're assuming that the kernel is always going to schedule the unsafe trajectory but
即假设内核总是调度不安全的轨迹
You can't assume that in fact it doesn't sometimes you just get lucky
事实上，你不能这样假设，因为有时候程序的结果是对的
And it turns out you have to call this function with a pretty big number in order to trip it up
事实上，你必须用一个相当大的数字作为 thread 函数的参数，才能得到错误的答案
So the it makes sense right
这好像有点道理
If usually what the kernel does is that
通常，内核调度的时机
I we can only schedule
内核可以调度
We can only reschedule a thread you know swap it out and schedule another thread in
内核可以重新调度一个线程，即将一个线程换下来，把另一个线程换上去
When there's some exception okay so that that passes control back to the kernel
只有当发生了异常，控制权被转移到内核时候，内核才能调度线程
So these exceptions are in two forms either calling system making system calls
这些异常有两种形式，系统调用
So that'll trap into the kernel so that's a form of exception
系统调用会陷入内核，这是一种异常形式
Or the timer interrupts goes off which transfers control back to the kernel
或者出现了定时器中断，将控制权转移回内核
So the timer is going off on intervals of like milliseconds
定时器会间隔相同的毫秒时间产生一个中断
Right so if we're just doing one iteration it in each thread
所以，如果我们只是在每个线程中进行一次迭代
When a thread gets executed the chances are very low that the timer is going to go off
当线程被执行时，发生定时器中断的可能性非常低
While that thread is executing you know it's its little loop
因为在循环中，我们只让 cnt++
But as we...and we're not making any system calls
循环中，我们没有进行任何系统调用
Right so there's nothing that, there's nothing...we're not passing control back into the kernel ourselves
所以，在程序中我们并没有将控制权转移到内核
So the only way the kernel is going to get access is if the timer interrupts goes off
因此，陷入内核的唯一方法就是产生了一个定时器中断
So if we're doing a very small number of iterations
因此，如果我们进行的迭代次数非常少
The probability that you know say here's the timer interval it's going off at intervals like this
在循环执行期间发生时钟中断的可能性很小，因为时钟中断是固定时间产生一次
Here this the probability we'd have to
如果我们想得到错误的运行结果
That's thread would have to been scheduled right before a timer interrupts will go off or to interrupt that one or two iterations
线程必须要在时钟中断发生前执行一两次循环
So it turns out we have to schedule
事实上
We have to call this function with a lot of within interrupts being fairly large
如果我们用一个大的数字去调用这个函数，让执行的时间变长
So that the probability of the timer interrupts going off during that
数字越大，执行过程中发生定时器中断的可能性
During that during that loop but gets increasingly large,that makes sense
就越大，大概就是这样一个分析
So the classic solution from this comes from the early 1960s
同步问题的经典解决方案来自 20 世纪 60 年代早期
One of the most famous computer scientists is a dutchman named as Edsger Dijkstra
由一位最著名的计算机科学家之一，一名叫 Edsger Dijkstra 的荷兰人
And he came up with the classical first solution to this problem which is what we're going to look at
他提出了这个问题的第一个解决方案，也就是我们今天要学的内容
Okay and it's still the first it's it's fundamental and very general purpose
这个解决方案是非常基础的
And there's been many iterations and variations on this idea
这个解决方案经过许多迭代，有一些其他的版本
But semaphores were the first and classic solution which we'll look at
但我们将要学习的信号量是这个问题的第一个，也是经典的解决方案
Okay so a semaphore is a non-negative global integer
好的，信号量是一个非负的全局整数
That's used as a synchronization variable by to kernel functions called P and V
信号量作为同步的变量，被两个内核函数 P 和 V 操作
Our two system calls called P and V
两个系统调用叫做 P 和 V
These P and V are correspond to the dutch words
P 和 V 对应于荷兰语 Proberen（测试）和 Verhogen（增加）
But we just call them P and V right you just have to learn what they do
我们简称为 P 和 V，你只需要了解这两个函数作用
So each of these takes as an argument a semaphore
这两个函数都以信号量作为参数
And the P operation has the following semantics
并且 P 操作具有以下语义
If s is nonzero
如果 s 不为零
Then decrement it by 1 and return immediately
将其减 1 并立即返回
And this test if it that it's nonzero
如果信号量是非零的
And the decrement occur atomically
就将其减一，并且这个操作是原子的
Okay so they'll never be interrupted
所以 P V 操作永远不会被中断
However if s is zero
但是如果 S 为零
Then suspend this thread
就会挂起这个线程
Until s becomes nonzero
直到 s 变为非零
And that thread then is restarted by a V operation
然后通过 V 操作重新启动该线程
Okay so if p if the semaphore is zero,P just blocks
好的，如果信号量为零，P 就会阻塞
It just gets suspended until it gets restarted by a V operation
线程会被挂起，直到它被 V 操作重新启动
And then after it restarts
然后重新执行 P 操作
The P operation now can decrement s by one and return control to the caller
现在 P 操作可以减 1 并将控制权返回给调用者
Okay the V operation just increments s by one
V 操作只将信号量增加 1
And this increment unlike that count++ that we looked at just looked at this that increment occurs atomically
这里的增加不像前面的 cnt++，这里的增加操作是原子的
Okay so it can never be interrupted
好的，它永远不会被打断
And then after it increments s
然后在它增加 s 之后
It checks to see if there's any threads that are blocked in a P operation
它会检查是否有线程阻塞在 P 操作上
So you can think of the kernel just keeps a queue of threads that are blocked in a P operation
你可以认为，内核维护了一个被 P 操作阻塞的线程队列
And the V operation after it increments s it checks that queue for any threads that were blocked
并且在 V 操作增加信号量之后，它会检查该队列是否有被 P 操作阻塞的线程
Because when they did the P operation the semaphore was zero
这些线程在执行 P 操作时，信号量为零
And then it restarts exactly one of those threads in some indeterminate order
然后它以某种不确定的顺序重新启动其中一个线程
Okay in some order that you can't,you can't assume
按照某种顺序，所以你不能假设按照某种顺序
It just picks one using some selection algorithm
内核使用某种选择算法从队列中选择一个线程
And it and then it it it unblocks the suspended  the suspended process
然后内核重启这个被 P 操作阻塞的线程
Okay which then completes its P operation by decrementing yes
然后 P 操作可以将信号量减 1
Okay this seems like really simple but it can be kind of hard to get your head around the first time you see it
这看起来很简单，但是第一次接触时可能会让你感到比较疑惑
So are there any questions about P and V
关于 P 和 V 有什么问题吗？
Okay so that the key idea that these definitions of P and V
这样定义 P 和 V 操作的主要目的是
Is that it imposes an invariant on the semaphores
让信号量获得一个信号量不变性的属性
Called the semaphore invariant which is s which is that for a semaphore s
信号量不变性，也就是对于一个信号量
Being operated on by P and V operations
只通过 P 和 V 操作对信号量进行操作的时候
s is always greater than or equal to zero
信号量的值总是大于或等于零
And that doesn't seem very exciting
这看上去似乎没有太大的作用
But it turns out this is a very useful property that will allow us to enforce mutual exclusion on these critical sections
但事实上，这是一个非常有用的属性，利用这个属性可以实现对临界区的互斥访问
So the P and V operations are provided by P threads
POSIX 标准定义了 P 和 V 操作的相关函数
In the form of three functions
提供了 3 个函数
There's a sem_init functions which initializes the semaphore to some value
sem_init 函数可以将信号量初始化为某个值
Okay so semaphore is can be initialized to any value greater than or equal to zero
信号量可以初始化为任何大于或等于零的值
sem_wait is the P operation and sem_post is the V operation
sem_wait 函数对应 P 操作，sem_post 函数对应 V 操作
Okay and because I'm old-school
因为我是一个老派的人
I provide wrapper functions for those in your cssapp.h file called P and V
所以我在 cssapp.h 文件中提供了两个包装函数 P 和 V
Okay it's also more compact to
使用这两个函数可以使代码更紧凑
Okay so recall a buggy program called badcnt.c
好的，让我们再看看 badcnt.c 这个有 bug 的程序
Which was giving us the wrong answers for count
这个 bug 会导致最后 cnt 的值错误
So how do we use semaphores to fix this program
那么我们如何使用信号量来修复这个程序
So the basic idea is to create a semaphore
基本的想法是创建一个信号量
Which is initialized to 1
然后将其初始化为 1
And so by definition we'll call any semaphore which is initialized to 1
根据定义，任何初始化为 1 的信号量
That's used for to provide mutual exclusion we'll call that a mutex
称为互斥锁，因为它用来提供互斥操作
Okay and this goes back to the early Dijkstra papers
这种叫法可以追溯到 Dijkstra 早期的论文
So we'll associate a unique mutex initialize to 1 for each shared variable in our program
因此，我们为程序中的每个共享变量提供一个唯一的互斥锁，即初始值为 1 的信号量
So in this case count,we have count,so we have one shared variable that we're concerned about
在我们这个程序中，我们只关心 cnt 这个共享变量
So we'll create one new text that will call mutex
因此，我们只创建一个称为 mutex 的互斥锁
And then you surround the critical section with respect to count
然后使用 P V 操作将临界区操作 cnt 的部分保护起来
With P, you call P then you execute the critical section and then you call V
也就是，你先调用 P，然后执行临界区，然后再调用 V
Now there's some terminology we'll use when we talk about semaphores
现在我们讲一下使用信号量时我们要用到的一些术语
So a binary semaphore is the semaphore whose value is always 0 1
首先是二进制信号量，它是一个信号量，其值始终为 0 1
And then a mutex is this sort is a binary semaphore that's being used to for mutual exclusion
然后是互斥锁（互斥量），即用来互斥的二进制信号量
The P operation is called locking the mutex
P 操作称为互斥锁加锁
Will refer to a V is sometimes unlocking or releasing the mutex
相应的，P 操作称为互斥锁解锁，或互斥锁释放
And if a process is holding the mutex then that means it's been locked but not released
如果进程持有互斥锁，那么这意味着互斥锁已经加锁，但未被释放
So mutexes and binary semaphore s are always initialized to 1
因此，互斥量和二进制信号量始终初始化为 1
Accounting semaphore and the mutex is used for mutual exclusion
互斥锁用于互斥
But you can also use semaphores to count sort of events in the system
但还有一种信号量叫做 counting semaphore，它可以用来对系统的事件计数
And often times for those accounting semaphores have sort of non values that are greater than 1
对于 accounting semaphore，信号量的值通常大于 1
Okay so for mutual exclusion
好，下面我们使用互斥锁
We'll to fix our program we create a new program called goodcnt.c
来修复我们的程序，我们创建一个名为 goodcnt.c 的新程序
And here we initialize a mutex
这里我们初始化一个互斥锁
Or we create a mutex and initialize it to 1
或者说，我们创建一个信号量，并将其初始化为 1
And then we surround the critical section which is the 3 assembly language instructions
然后我们使用 PV 操作包围临界区，即实现 cnt++ 的
Embodied that implement this cnt++ instruction
3 条汇编指令
We surround it with a P followed by it by a V
在 cnt++ 前调用P，在 cnt++ 后调用 V
And if we do that we always get the right answer
如果我们这样做，我们总能得到正确的答案
But you know P&V are system calls
但是因为 P 和 V 是系统调用
So there's overhead associated with these
因此，P V 操作是有较大的开销的
So they're not free
使用 P V 进行同步不是没有代价的
In fact they're orders of magnitude this program runs two orders of magnitude slower than the incorrect buggy version
事实上，这个程序比错误的版本慢了两个数量级
All right so so why do these mutex work
那么为什么使用互斥锁能够修复程序呢
So here we've got a progress graph now where we've decorated a program with P and V operations
现在看这一个进度图，这个进度图对应于使用 PV 操作同步后的程序
So we put the P before the critical section we execute the critical section and then we call V
所以我们在临界区之前调用 P，然后执行临界区，然后我们调用 V
And now if you were to look you remember P and V,P increments
现在，P 会减少信号量
The sum of P decrement the semaphore V increments of semaphore
P 会减少信号量，而 V 会增加信号量
So if you were just to look at the value of that semaphore for every point  in the execution state space
因此，如果你记录执行状态空间中每个点的信号量值
You'd get these,you'd get these values
你会得到这些信号量的值
So here we initialize the semaphore at the origin we initialized it to 1
原点的信号量初始化为 1
So the value of a semaphore at the origin is 1
因此，原点信号量的值为 1
And let's say we just move along
然后程序开始执行
So we're just executing thread 1
我们现在只是执行线程 1
So after H(1) the semaphore is 1
因此，在 H(1) 之后，信号量为 1
We do the P the semaphore is 1,so P just decrement sit and it proceeds
然后我们执行 P 操作，信号量减 1，然后程序继续执行
So now the semaphore value becomes 0
所以现在信号量变为 0
And it remains zero until we execute the V
在我们执行 V 之前信号量一直保持为 0
And when we finished executing the V
当我们完成 V 操作
The semaphore now is 1 again
信号量又变回 1 了
Okay so if we go through a similar reasoning
类似的
If we look at the trajectory to get to any point in this state space
我们看一下这个状态空间中的每个点的信号量值
So let's say this point right here
比如说这一个点（鼠标位置）
So to get there we could execute thread 1 up to this point  finish the L(1)
要到达这个点，我们可以先让线程 1 执行到 L(1)
And then execute H(2)
然后执行线程 2 的 H(2)
And then do the at this point the semaphore is 0
然后在这一点（鼠标位置）上信号量为 0
And then P decrements the semaphore so now it's -1
然后 P 减少信号量，所以现在信号量是 -1
But that's impossible that can't happen
但那不可能发生
Because P blocks, remember if the semaphore is 0 P blocks
因为 P 操作会阻塞，因为信号量为 0 了
It doesn't decrement
它不能减少
It okay so the semantics of the P operation prohibits this transition
所以 P 操作的语义禁止这种转换
It prohibits this transition to the state where the semaphore is zero to a state where it would be -1
它禁止向信号量从零的状态转换为 -1 的状态
And so it creates what we call a forbidden region so these points in the state space
因此 PV 操作创造了禁止区，禁止区对应于状态空间中的
Where the semaphore would have a value of -1 are are infeasible
信号量值为 -1 的地方，因为这些地方是不可到达的
That can never be reached by the definition of P and V
根据 P 和 V 的定义，这些地方永远无法达到
Ok so this forms a forbidden region around the unsafe region
好的，这就形成了一个包围不安全区的禁止区
And in doing so provides mutually exclusive access to the critical sections in each thread
这样就可以提供对临界区的互斥访问
Okay so if
好的
So this is the fundamental reason why P(s) and V(s)  can be used to provide mutually exclusive access
因此，这是 P(s) 和 V(s) 可用于提供互斥访问的根本原因
So many questions on this
对这一点有什么疑问吗
I explained it so clearly that there's no questions
看来我解释得很清楚，大家都没有问题
All right good well you get to go...you get to leave early then work on your malloc lab
好的，你们可以下课，然后完成 malloc lab 了
So
所以
All right so
好的
We'll see you Monday we're going to look at sort of some advanced topics
那我们下周一见，下周一我们要学习「同步」的一些高级主题
This was like, first introduction to synchronization
这节课只是对同步进行了简单介绍
On Tuesday we'll look at more advanced topics in synchronization in ways
周二，我们会介绍「同步」的一些高级主题
Ways that you can use semaphores for to
主要是使用信号量
Provide other more interests other interesting kinds of synchronization for your programs
来为你的程序提供一些「同步」
Okay
好的